Résumé

ARIF AHMED

"Tenth Tower" Level-8, Green Housing Society, Polash Bari, Novi Nagor, Savar, Dhaka Cell: +880 1676 449766, 1712 908809

E-mail: arifahmedgmo@gmail.com, arif.ahmed@epicbd.com



CAREER OBJECTIVE

Intend to build a career in leading corporate with committed & dedicated people, which will help me to explore myself fully and realize my potential. Willing to work as a key player in challenging and creative environment.

I've able to working physically experience in Garments Industry 18 years and 8 years lead the Factory with Operations. Factory overall responsible all dept. with Operations Management, Industrial Engineering (IE), Planning, Sample, Floor Management, Development, Factory Operating, Merchandising, Manufacturing, Store, Warehouse, Quality, Inspection to Garments industry & Production at Woven & Denim (Top/Bottom), Jacket, Knit, Lingerie, Underwear, Swimwear, Bikinis... etc.

CAREER SUMMARY

Cost-conscious and analytical with history of success.

Optimizing quality and production processes in fast-paced manufacturing environments.

Increase productivity, quality, profitability through keen data analysis and process, significantly improve operations and provide efficient resolution of production issues. Identify Opportunities for honing safety standards and maximizing ROI. Completing projects accurately on time within budget. Outstanding communication, problem solving and relationship in management skills.

I had to worked in **development project** Garments Industry in **Modular System**, **Trolley System**, PBS System (Linear layout & Group layout), **LEAN System** (Kaizen, 5s, 6s) etc. Also, I've to able in factory setup, organized, system procedure & **development with day-night shifting**.

Areas of Expertise

Sewing Technology~ Quality Assurance ~ Production Planning ~ Modular Manufacturing Lean Manufacturing ~ Supply Chain Management ~ Just-in-Time (JIT) ~ 5S and Kaizen Cost Reduction & Avoidance ~ Statistical Process Control (SPC) ~ Process Redesign

TRAINING - GARMENTS TECHNOLOGY

GHERZI GARMENTING - CONSULTANTS AND ENGINEERS TO THE INDUSTRY

I've worked experience with "GHERZI Consultancy Firm" is a global management consulting and engineering company. GHERZI is the leader for strategic development and expansion of companies in the textile industry, from production to retail. There services range from Engineering of new factories to strategy consulting as well as corporate finance

Successfully completed 1 year on job training garments technology. I've worked development factory in JMS Garments LTD, JMS Group, CEPZ, Chittagong. Following developed is **GHERZI GARMENTING** and was training by **'RAZVAN IONELE'** and field working **'MIHAI CARMEN SIMONA'** & **'BADCA KARINA'** with team to be used in **GHERZI PROJECT by GHERZI CONSULTANT.**

https://www.facebook.com/gherzi.garmenting (see the web page are evidence Dec'2013)

Training Session:

a) Industrial Engineeringc) Product Development

b) Planningd) Cutting

e) Sewing Technologies

f) Finishing

g) Quality Assurance

h) Technical & Training Centre.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

EPIC GROUP. GREEN TEXTILE LTD (GTL-2) & PGCL.

- Factory GTL: Nijhuri, Baraid, Bhaluka, Mymensingh, Bangladesh.



Present Designation: General Manager - Operations (Head of Factory & Operations) vi

Date of Joining : 01/11/2021 - Continue Department : Production & Operations.

Item : Woven/Denim (Top & Bottom) & knit.

Organization : **Epic Group**. Green Textile Ltd (GTL-2) & Pearl Garments Company Ltd (PGCL).

PAGE TWO

Selected Contributions (PGCL, EPIC GROUP):

- **COMPANY'S OPERATIONS**: The position of its operating performance for the half year' ended last month 2022 compared to previous half year are given below in pcs:
 - Half Yearly capacity 3.33 M. (Per month 0.555 M)
 - Achievement half yearly 3.030 M (2021-2022), Previous half year achieving yearly 2.664 M. Last Half Year Increase Productivity & Performance 0.366 M.
- Successfully implementation and execution of project in development factory and right people work on right place. Man, machine ration to 1:80.
- Since'22, On Time delivery 100%, Order to ship 100%, Order to woven 101%. External Quality pass rate 100%, External Audit pass rate 100%. Final inspection report 1st & 3rd party woven/Denim 100% (OQL-2.5).
- Implement IE concepts with improve productivity & achieving 2.46 pcs/ per operator/ per hour.
- Managing PGCL Factory RMG unit of 1600 work forces & Business worth \$ 50 M (CM \$ 7.6 M)
- Responsible & achieving for effective Production planning and efficient avg. 92%.

* New Asia Group. Salek Textile Ltd (RMG UNIT).

Salek Textile Ltd. (RMG Unit)
A Sister Consern of New Asia Group

- Factory: Holding # 122, Sinabha, Kaliakoir, Shofipur, Gazipur, Dhaka-1751

Designation : General Manager - Factory (Head of Factory & Operations) v

Date of Joining : 02/05/2020 - 31/10/2021

Department : Factory Production & Operations.
Item : Woven/Denim (Top & Bottom) & knit.

Organization : Salek Textile Ltd (RMG Unit), STL Denim, New Asia Group, Gazipur, BD.

Developed in the factory operations standards to increase production & minimize nonviable added time to reduce cost manufacturing. Monitoring with analyzed workflow, processes, procedures, line activities, identifying and resolving bottlenecks to maximize efficiency.

Created to be costing models to support customer proposals and cost reduction initiatives. Served on a quality assurance team, developing guidelines, procedures to improve standards and performance.

Factory are working Day - Night shifting.

Selected Contributions (STL RMG UNIT):

- **COMPANY'S OPERATIONS**: The position of its operating performance for the year' ended 30th June, 2021 compared to previous year are given below in pcs:
 - Yearly capacity 6.6 M. (Per month 0.55 M)
 - Achievement yearly 4.206 M (2020-2021), Previous year achieving yearly 3.897 M. (2019-2020). Last Year Increase Productivity & Performance 0.309 M.
 - Capacity Utilization This year 63.73% (2020-2021) & previous year 59.05% (2019-2020). Increase & Performance Capacity Utilization 4.68 %.
- Capital Expenditure was incurred during the last two years financial statement in million. This year tk. 412.31 M (2020-2021) & Previous year tk. 930.33 M (2019-2020).

Saving cost yearly achievement tk. 518.02 M

- FINANCIAL RESULTS: The Company's operating financial results, as compared to the previous year are summarized in Million as Gross profit tk. 423.67 M (2020-2021) & previous year tk.157.82 M (2019-2020). Gross Margin Ratio 9.28% (2020-2021) and previous year 4.07% (2019-2020). Improvement & increase financial last year gross margin ratio 5.21%.
- Successfully implementation and execution of project in development factory and right people work on right place. This reduces direct manpower 50%. **2:25 man machine ration to 1:75.**
- **Since Dec'20,** On Time delivery 100%, Order to ship 100%, Order to woven 101%. External Quality & Audit pass rate 100%. Final inspection report 1st & 3rd party woven/Denim 100% (AQL-2.5).
- Increase machine earning by 25%, improving efficiency above 90% and reducing yarn waste less than 1.5%. Improve productivity & achieving 3.03 pcs/ per operator/ per hour.
- Managing STL Factory RMG unit of 1200 work forces & Business worth \$ 65 M (CM \$ 7.8 M)
- **TECHNOLOGIES:** Successfully implementation & running Auto CAD, Auto layer, Auto Pocket attach, Auto pocket Hem, Auto pocket Iron, Auto Loop attach, Hi tech Waist band, auto "J" stitch and Oracle ERP system.
- MACHINE: Axios System Assyst, Version- RUG2017 and V-stitcher, Pocket Setters, Pocket Heming, Auto Loops, 'J' Stitch, High Speed FOA (Auto), High Speed Kansai, All Machines with Auto Thread, Trimmers and Servo Motors etc.

$\mathsf{A}\mathsf{RIF}\,\mathsf{A}\mathsf{H}\mathsf{MED}$

- New customer on boarded New Times, Mango, Synergies, Bestedo etc.
- Get Factory Certified by BSCI, Sedex, Accord, RAB, OCS, RCS/BCI/OEKO-tex, HITT, OCS, RCF, WCA. GOTX.

Responsibility & Quantifiable Achievements:

- Managing the entire factory garments operations and ensure that production standards with profitably.
- Responsible & achieving effective Production planning and efficiency 90%.
- > To make necessary arrangement of training for the subordinates in order to increase the production capability by following modern production procedures (Automation machinery use).
- > To implement price-controlled policy in every stage of production, so that production cost is reduced.
- Order status monitoring & regular schedule meeting with merchandising & marketing for order planning/optimal pricing/production/lead time/shipment.
- Improving profitability by identifying cost reduction opportunities through Integrated Planning Information and analysis.

AZIM GROUP (WOVEN DIVISION), CHITTAGONG.

49, (NP) Kalurghat Heavy I/A, Chittagong, Bangladesh.

Azim Group : General Manager - Production (Head of Factory) IV

: 05/06/2017 - 30/04/2020 Date of Joining Department : Factory Production & Operations.

: Woven & Denim (Top/Bottom) & Shirt. Item

: Azim Group (Woven Division) Chittagong, Kalurghat, Bangladesh. Organization

Selected Contributions (Azim Group):

Designation

- Yearly achieving in 20 lines woven/Denim/Shirt/Cargo production 8 million pcs.
- Successfully implementation and execution of project in development factory. This reduces direct manpower 60%. 2:50 man machine ration to 1:90.
- Managing Factory of 2500 work force & Business worth \$ 80 M (CM= \$ 20M).
- Since Feb'19 to Nov'20, On Time delivery 100%, Order to ship 100%, Order to woven 100.5%, External Quality pass rate 100%, External Audit pass rate100%. Final inspection report 3rd party woven/Denim 100% (AQL-2.5).
- Increase machine earning by 15%, improving efficiency above 65% and reducing yarn waste less than 1.0%. Improvement productivity & achieving 1.23 pcs/ per operator/ per hour.
- Successfully 6 lines setup Basic 5 pkt in modular system for production and save in time style change over. Achieve business 0.25 million pcs export capacity/per month.
- Increase productivity & Efficiency with Quality standards through developing Standard Operating Procedure (SOP) & Reduce in Style Change over Time (SCOT).
- Get Factory Certified by BSCI, OEKO-Tex, RAB, Sedex, GRS, RCS, OCS, GOTS, ACCORD, ALLIANCE.

LZ GROUP. LZ FASHION WEAR LTD.

Plot#154, DEPZ (EXTN), Gonakbari, Savar, Dhaka.

Designation GM – IE, Planning & Production (Head of Factory) III

: 02/08/2014 - 03/06/2017 Date of Joining Department : Factory Production & Operations.

Item : Woven & Denim (Top/Bottom), Jacket, Knit, Lingerie, Underwear & Swimwear.

: LZ Fashion Wear Ltd, LZ Group, DEPZ (EXTN), Bangladesh. Organization

Selected Contributions:

- Collaborated with senior management on Business Process Reengineering (BPR) efforts, gaining 25% increase in productivity and quality. Overall factory present efficiency level 65%.
- Created and implemented efficiency enhancements to generate more than 30% improvement through associated cost reductions.
- **Yearly achieving** in production 6.5 million pcs.
- Successfully implementation and execution of project in development factory. This reduces direct manpower 60%. 2.2 man machine ration to 1:6.
- Increase machine earning by 30%, improving efficiency above 60% and reducing yarn waste less than 1.5%.



PAGE FOUR

❖ JMS GROUP LTD. JMS GARMENTS LTD & MODISTE (BD) LTD.



- Plot#1-4, Sector#6, CEPZ, Chittagong - 4223.

Designation : Sr. Manager - IE & Planning (Responsible in Production) II

Date of Joining : 05/03/2011 - 31/07/2014 Department : IE, Planning & Production.

Item : Woven & Denim (Top/Bottom), Jacket, Knit, Lingerie, Underwear & Swimwear.

Organization : JMS Garments Ltd & Modiste (BD) Ltd. JMS Group, CEPZ, Bangladesh.

Factory is working Day Double shifting. (6am-2pm-10pm)

Selected Contributions:

 Promoted Lean System & Modular System (Trolley) and implementation though out each operation with current data.

 Applied sewing new technology & automated sewing machine to basic 5 pocket, chino, cargo trousers, woven shirt & knit items.

Reduce labor costs fixed yearly by \$1.12 million dollars through effective process streamlining, increased work floor space by 25% through.

Successfully implementation and execution of project in Factory new equipment setup & development.
 This reduces direct manpower 70%. 2.4 man machine ration to 1:7.

❖ PACIFIC JEANS LTD. UNIVERSAL JEANS LTD.

Plot#9-11, Sector#6/A, CEPZ, Chittagong -4223.

Designation : Manager – IE (Executive to Promoted)

Date of Joining : 02/01/2005 - 28/02/2011
Department : Industrial Engineering

Item : Woven & Denim (Bottom & Cargo).

Organization : Pacific Jeans Ltd, Universal Jeans Ltd, CEPZ, Bangladesh.

Training Summary:

Training Title	Topic	Institute	Country	Location	Year	Duration
On Job Training	Garments Technologies & Training	JMS Garments LTD Bangladesh Plot#1		Plot#1-4, Sector#6, CEPZ, Chittagong.	7 7 2012	
Computer Course	Computer Hardware, Software & Internet	Online Net Training Center	Net Training Center Bangladesh City Tower, 1st floor, 19/ Anderkilla, Chittagong.		2009	1 year
GED	General Education Development	Gateway Education Consultants - Under the Board of American Education Council	Bangladesh	GEC Circle, Chittagong	2005	6 Month's

Academic Qualification:

Exam Title	Concentration/Major	Institute	Result	Pass Year	Duration	Achievement	
Bachelor of Commerce		Chittagong Govt.	Second	2008	3	Pass	
(BCom)	Commerce	City Collage	Class	2006			
HSC	Colonas	Chittagong Govt.	Second	2002	2	Pass	
пъс	Science	City Collage	Division	2002			
222	Colones	South Hali Shahar	Second	2000	2	Pass	
SSC	Science	high school, CTG	Division	2000			

Specialization:

Fields of Specialization	Description Top Customer				
 Customer Satisfaction & Relationship Management 					
 Garment Technology& Maintenance 	I had to physically worked in my record by Top Customer				
 Industrial & Production Engineering 	as ADIDAS, Lululemon, Zara, M & S, VF Asia, C&A, H&M,				
 Production/ Operation Management 	UFI, Verner, Celio, Target, TOMMY Hilfiger, Tchibo, GFG,				
 Project Management 	ADLER, WILSON, DECILLION, ESPRIT, TESCO, NEWTIMES,				
 Cost and Profit Analysis 	NEXT, OTF, GAP, Levi's, Old Navy, AMEREX, GARAN,				
 Garments Production, Planning & Organizing 	UNIQLO, Walmart, GP, Li & Fung, PVH, Perry Ellis,				
 Industrial & Production Engineering 	American Eagle, Decathlon, Asmara, UFI, LANCET,				
 Production Control Activities & Tactics 	AMAZON, Duluth Trading, Jessy Penny, Red point, Gulden				
 Production Woven & Denim (Top/Bottom), Kids & Jacket. 	Pending, CHAPS, Columbia, Terranova, ODINTEX, Group Zanier, Propower, Edcon, Reliance, Whispering Smith,				
 Production & Lean project in Knit, Lingerie, Underwear, Swimwear, Bikinisetc. 	Woolworth, Dotti, New Yorker, Jay Jays, Bershka,				
 Health Safety & Environment 	Synergies, KB, WM (Free Assembly)etc.				
Lean Management					

Personal Information

Father's Name
Mother's Name
Spouse's Name
Date of Birth

Shibbir Ahmed.
Late Sofura Begum.
Ratna Akter Tishita.
9th March, 1984.

Family Address (Chittagong): Flat No-3/C, Level-3, k N Tower, Nearby Kutub Bhabon,

Mohammedpur, Muradpur, P/O: Chandgaon,

Thana: Punchlish, District: Chittagong.

Permanent Address : Mirza House, Village: Mirzapur, P/O: Boktermonshi Bazar,

Thana: Sonagaji, District: Feni-3900.

Nationality : Bangladeshi by Birth.

Religion : Islam
Marital Status : Married
Height : 5'7"

Smart National ID No : 910 355 7915 Passport no : BM 0177674 Blood Group : AB (+ve)

REFERENCES

Dayan Thushara

Group CEO (STL, UFL & DAL)
Salek Textile Ltd (RMG Unit),
STL Denim, New Asia Group Ltd.
Tower 117, House#117, Tejaon, Dhaka

Mobile: +88 01730 037388
Email: dayanthushara@gmail.com

Sevana Ravindra

Vice President Green Textiles Ltd, Epic Group. Nijhuri, Baraid, 2 no Meduari, Bhaluka, Mymensingh, Bangladesh.

Mobile: +880 1741 592041 +91 99520 88780

Email: ravindransk@gmail.com

I, the undersigned, certify that, to the best of my knowledge and belief, this Curriculum Vita correctly described me, my qualifications and experience.

SIGNATURE....(Arif Ahmed)